5th ODI from the VB series of the 2003
2004 series being played at Brisbane
India skipper Saurav Ganguly won the
toss and elected to bat saref Ganguly is
such in toluca VVS Laxman and Rahul
Dravid
for the linchpin of the Indian batting
lineup while the young base Arsenal
consisted of Ashish Nehra ephod Burton
and Lakshmipathy Balaji all Ronda
Rohan Gavaskar was also making his debut
for Team India Australia played with
Adam Gilchrist Matthew Hayden Ricky
Ponting and Andrew Symonds leading them
batting attack
Brad Williamson Jason Gillespie and
Brett leave a part of a formidable
bowling lineup so all in readiness in
center and time now to go to the
commentators
[Music]
it's rooms
Iseman Phil
yes four boys all swing the other way
this time and all of a sudden it's 9/4 I
Ganguly didn't like it he flinched there
and look at it swing light after the bat
it was on the way across the left-hander
he didn't like the look of it he fended
at it and watch it dip now the
atmosphere is conducive to plenty
in the air and they're off the same
maybe this wickets got a little bit in
it
yeah
the hands of Gauri
puts it down
first over
in swinging line out swinging for buys
gets it right the outside edge strike
today me Martin
hey guys go away for fall under the
tulips in he went to the drive got a
good genuine outside edge vegetable hot
for third sweater
Bunnings had a good go at it wouldn't
surprise me to see the Australian to
catch these but not the easy ones one
foot in it again a tentative push by ten
dukkha no conviction about Italy a
perfect Barling by Williams
squeezy Mart asked the question on fire
[Applause]
once again the footwork
not convincing yet Gillespie has been
swinging it to the left doesn't swing
this time Tendulkar caught in front of
the stumps just a bit high the umpire
says and very very correctly
something bigs going to happen here
Kimberly is like a Cat on a Hot Tin Roof
but he's looking at every gap that's out
there he's looking in the air looking
to go over the top hasn't been able to
do it yet something's gonna give itself
there gonna be him or Gillespie the
Australians are taunting him on the
offside they're asking him to hit over
the top of them
he does beautifully well play one dance
over the ride full
haha what a beauty he's played and
missed this a couple of times and now he
crunches one straight out of the middle
don't worry about taunting him he had it
on his mind ever since starting this
innings that's the shot he wants
[Applause]
and water from later that that almost
carried is that far from being six
themselves and width on the on side
Frieda's arms up and bang
he goes again that's gonna fence park
aeri what
yes it does well played game bill
the history
I think to the biggest square boundaries
we'll see in the country as well here in
Brisbane he's made it look
around Brisbane Creek burn now is very
wide and the ropes are in five or ten
meters but still as big as we've seen
sliced up ish Li and long Ritz when you
get a DS body look he's going to the on
side that's beautifully striking a
caravel yards over the right
all of a sudden 10 runs of two
deliveries
that's absolutely smashed and along the
ground the hallway
Brad Williams might have said something
to ganguly last over and Billy didn't
really need to respond after hitting
that shot three big shots through the
offside in recent times from Ganguly to
off Gillespie and now one off Brad
Williams and it's a battle that Ganguly
has won I think let's react this summer
it seems to me the Australians have said
well let's keep the ball wide of off
stop - Ganguly and eventually we'll get
him out now
Damian Marc dropped him earlier to stop
all this afternoon it's good a ball
about obviously a quick departure for
Ganguly Williams
the last site
Ganguly is gone with the short pitch
delivery right at him
[Applause]
excellent
Fred Williams it's a line though I think
Australia should be bowling it even
captain for a lot longer over leg stuff
not outside off stump the Indian captain
who loves playing square the wicket on
the offside has nowhere to go
Brad Williams has picked him up so
there's three big shots he's with the
important ball by Brad Williams at 4:18
one for 37
basket shot not ducking on this occasion
[Applause]
brings up the 54 India lovely way to
bring it up too soon VVS Laxman dak a
few of these short balls
Jason less people saw that very ill got
away in front of squarely almost off the
tower the bat and saw it that well
that's a grandchild
slow
1:54
[Applause]
Paul started become thick and fast now
Tendulkar has hurt his ankle there
implying that shot
I think he's asking for some type
[Applause]
was only going to need a tape or a
runner with one of the two this is a
beautiful back foot square cut I will
see quite a lot of pain when he has to
put his weight on that back right foot
it's when the ankle be tested the most
and obviously it's warm at the moment
she ate
take that it's also controlled pushing
off flies back foot shot so he may well
need a runner as well then there's only
one man who can run for him that's the
captain because he's out don't send in
any of the guys still to come
I was sore again Julie I'll be Sydney at
all sorts of doctors and medical staff
to get it right
I can't imagine saw I've gained really
been cleaned around here's that square
cuts beautiful shot it just has to put
so much weight and really all is right
on that right foot
about quite a bit of pain Sachin
Tendulkar
[Applause]
right shot as well this is the diner for
Australia
you think well I don't want to be
running too much I better hit all
boundaries
[Applause]
the way the injured players do eyesight
Cricut Terms and you think you've got
him down and out he was maybe thinking
about retiring hurt thinking about
getting a runner out there or suddenly
I worry too much about what to the ball
as being barges players and shots
[Applause]
[Music]
very straight on that shirts white out
of the middle of the bat
and thought it was going for four when
he hit it and then
started to accelerate a little bit
but five Bambi's in the last two and a
half hours worrying sign for the
Australians lovely shots that stood to
attention there such a tend to look up
glorious painting
seventy-two
that's a great shot it really is in
top-class warm VVS Laxman
[Music]
well that's beautiful apply it in its
fall
for the fields when it
toy moves that the ball is going so fast
he actually took off as Damian Martin
there took off in the ball actually went
flying past him before he had time
[Applause]
that's he's off century that's intended
gobbles down for a single
across India and sitting in this ground
only supporters be very happy with this
and he's not finished yet
we were the injured veteran
hustle and bustle too much that he's
made a brilliant 50 from just fifty
three balls carrying an injury
that's gotta be close a little shake of
the head now
oh and very nearly had him run out as
well
Laxman very close to being at lbw and
then I think a direct hit would have had
him out run out he was I think just
contemplating what the umpire was about
to say about this have a look at this
[Music]
well I gotta say that it looked very
close looking at it live it looked just
as close on the replay and then this is
what happened no one anywhere near there
he realizes he's out of his ground and
had that hit the stumps he would have
been out run out so close calls every
which faithful Exmouth
in the avid side beautifully pride I
have to run for that wafted off drive
superb placement
[Applause]
shut
once again
lovely still body when heating the shot
and a steelhead snow over balancing the
end of the shot was not so much
premeditated but was in the back of his
mind
in the end that important Bob always got
him again
[Applause]
it has brought a smile
the face of a new Simon's he's got in
before in
didn't spin slid straight on sachin
tenduikar meat on midwicket but all they
got was the two ends of Andy Symons 86
with an injury
Horton Belt Simon's two for 147
this is now the 33rd over beautifully
placed aren't they
like you garage she's the one I'd like
to see play well he's a magnificent
player when he goes very strong vers
Mustique lat this might go to the
boundary for for he's got that into the
right place yes it's gone well that's so
much needed boundary
very quick learner royal Dravid the
Simon's beat him with a quicker one last
over and then got the next quicker one
away and now he's got the slow one wide
of Haydn is 54 VVS Laxman
[Applause]
cool
your Crist is annoyed but no-slip
posthumous to the 211
it's good tonight
[Applause]
and good combination to for 236
11:54 Rahul Dravid
compared to the run a bolt just the one
boundary very history it was to four to
forty trillion
[Applause]
[Music]
first ball quickly was over smashed to
deep point coming back for two
crush the ball was in
the lecture was certainly struggling
Dravid 1 & 2 from the moment he hit the
ball not so sure Laxman's non-striker's
in was all that clean
aaden's a specialist on the rope he's
there because of his big arm strong flat
arm good angles bails down is the bat in
or out brettly did really well as a high
ball over the stamps if Ricky Ponting
moved his right arm we'd be right
mornings when exam just in the wrong
spot their bowels are off now
very difficult now he's got to have some
part of that bat over the line
Matthew Hayden's very good at cutting
the angles down to the balls and the
balls
it doesn't circle the bully run straight
to the ball what's the Arthur done per
se out
decision
tied ones fast quick to the ball and
he's got a good arm
much beauty balm again Santa costume for
rats
[Applause]
brettly previous one just mr. Stumpf's
that much mr. Stumpf's was willing gone
for four to four to five three
[Music]
I
he's caught that one that'll be for
maximum is riding for the small boy
[Applause]
fifty to sixty one
that's in the air and this beat is to
square though
[Music]
Rice's to item six
[Applause]
two bands
two balls for laxman this one not Brent
lead
last fall we face for me and javis over
and also put away it's in there let's
pick the gap between the two men one
square leg and one midwicket raced away
before history has just put the third
man out inside the circle to play an
extra man on the leg side boundary still
didn't work
in between Haven and Martin Martin on
the left of screen was well inside the
Rope he needs to be careful about that I
don't see any advantage of being 15 or
20 inside the rope as we speak they've
gone back to the old stuff Martin back
up into the circle third man gone back
to the rope the top left of screen
you'll see a man down
now again before more it's good hitting
from Ronald rather
[Applause]
working the ball
it's two boundaries in a row right where
Damien Martin was brilliant stroke play
seems to be able to place an at will
pretty ordinary bowling by in Harvey
right in the slot just brought that man
up you can't afford to bowl there needed
to be up a little fuller this one could
well be a Williams
a little disappointed they didn't hit
a good job for India
it hits the more difficult of the two
before
the ball before then gets the low full
toss hits it off the inside edge trying
to go straight over the bowlers head
inside edge to widest and shorty Schmidt
on on gravid not happy
the Australians will take it 13 balls to
go 3 4 to 8
[Applause]
all beautifully hit
it's a great plan of watch VVS Laxman
they are righted into the night x94
but hope brettly is trying to bowl your
cos that's it these ball bounces now in
slot balls I've never seen a ball come
out of the middle of the bat so well is
that that is flush out of the middle of
the band gives he stumps up Andrew
Symonds is that fielder who makes no
impact in the ball bang that's six to
eight inches from the tower the bat is
the middle I reckon expand
[Applause]
flick that alright got better than one
let's go fool
the wrists
[Applause]
this wonderful banning 13 off this over
so far
as figures up into the 80s
no rickets next to his name
the big lofty back lift Yuvraj Singh
hits it up there is about to throw his
hands at the ball looking for a full
ball hit something on his hip Chinese
mine whips with the wrists
before they fiddled with their fine leg
fields been a couple of times but India
have been after Platt square or finer
whatever's needed last ball
dolly this time Whitley 147 case
before spending a few brash seen
brettly we were finished with figures in
1 483 from his 10 ohms
but right now what he was looking for
this time you've rehearsing he got the
short one the long ball before looking
for the full of one this time it's the
full of one why light on it base of
middle stump that's a good idea all for
[Applause]
last fall the news for $40.99 Lakshman
or type that
it's well over the infield one two three
bounces into the right and that's a
brilliant hundred
yes Laxman
allspice brings it up from the last four
leanings
has three one night
all scored against Australian worth
[Laughter]
welcome back into that room is wrong
Galvez got to his three balls meant a
lot to India and to that man VVS Laxman
three figures would have been reached
Australian struggled in the field
very good batting pitch because driving
and Laxman gave them
Betty before from India
led by that man VVS Laxman first one day
hundred here in Australia his third his
career finish up after their fifty hours
after winning the toss batting first
Julian Tendulkar started Welton DoCoMo
86 also injured himself in the process
driving a very useful 74 but VVS Laxman
their 103 from 113 all the bowlers apart
from probably Jason Gillespie suffered
Gillespie bail well 10 overs for 40 but
Brett Lee won 483 from 10 and even even
harvey who generally is remise early in
the one day as one for 61 from his 10-4
for 303 India so Australia will need to
make 304 runs tonight
if i had to do that and he destroyed a
run rate of around about 6.08 runs per
over
[Music]
to get to fort
which is good layout feel relatively
fast
[Applause]
because of his
a great sale
Paulo G the Phils and who gave a very
good chase unfortunately his little
flick took the ball over the rover
excellent timing there from Matthew
Hayden
to a Scottish thing
enough to show at the boundary
era has seen all this before good
attempt there by Yuvraj Singh point
era was attacked in the World Cup final
by this combination
and then they went after him in the TV s
cup when he was coming back from injury
he really needs to find a way to curb
these two
[Applause]
but it's still for nun 429
close enough
the American
first when sword whizzing away
at a point but it beat the man on the
third man boundary in relative comfort
this is perfect example of his glorious
timing
safe
it's good sensible batting all the
Creole except two must be inside that
fielding circle or fielding area that's
marked out
[Applause]
the Indian bowlers must have known that
this was going to happen a little bit of
swing there for pattern which will
encourage him
tonight sit meet on
[Applause]
is the one they wanted well
but she has it all there's excitement
he's gone down on his knees
you'll push the man miss cueing there at
a time when Australia had taken 46 of
the bottles
let's the sort of reward you get when
you came to have evolved
in spies we're really going up
[Applause]
4:46
as Hitler through the field
while it's a strength of math you hire
such a big man
it's not the middle
to reference again and the Queenslanders
out of their seats they loving every
second of this hatin can do no wrong
here I tell you
there I've just got to see it penetrate
the feel the chances are when it does
that it's going to go for four you're
right bully is a strong black stone we
find to Kappa Kappa that's poor
could be five Laurent she went two weeks
again he could even want a Beautif
that is so frustrating he beats him all
ends up one ball
then he's get smashed through the covers
next one this is a good shot from
wanting I'm so out there a little bit on
the app boy definitely ever go out there
[Music]
it's a beautiful shot
dupa do it now it's hides turn so strong
Tommy spotter
superb stroke and the ball are doing the
right thing that's the time to quickly
swivel around and go back your mark have
a look at this right off the middle of
the bat beautifully timed as a mid on
there but it was just a little bit too
wide
before more usually 510 thumbs up the
era back
Lane goes to 49 that's one 478
[Applause]
where is his 50
thirty two I don't know feed you know
together
if you want to
you don't need to score a hundred yet to
get a standing ovation
[Applause]
really entertained them and they're on
their feet they have been they've been
be needing force
[Applause]
it should be
is that
[Applause]
maybe a Mexican spike some patching a
very disappointing shot from Ricky
Ponting
don't quite understand it actually I
think all he needed to do was to knock
it around for ones and twos he's trying
to hit that over square leg and
unfortunately it's gone straight up
Laxman was cool wasn't he have a look at
this target as clean as a whistle
he's a great batsman Barry's pretty safe
as well when it comes to the field and I
think they've enjoyed that one they
enjoy getting rid of Ponting - down 486
[Applause]
because it's gonna be on Grand Finals
for six
horses cricket citizen
[Applause]
this is a wonderful shot just have a
look at this straight down the ground
actually advancing down the ground again
and smashing him straight
[Applause]
yes he loves that shot doesn't he loves
the covered ride he's gone for it at
wedding whistling just above the ground
like a rocket was going towards backward
point
beautifully taken Yuvraj Singh makes a
big difference in the covers to the side
this is what he said to him good luck
have a good luck mate have a good luck
good one mate daddy went and a look
I'm out there this is the shot he played
straight to your garage who's sniffle
the catch now the Indians are just
slightly in front yes three four ninety
four
the cover drivers only small gap there
is
I just planted beautiful tonight
so boundary number 9 for him really has
used the fact that the field is up
inside the circle
Catching cover man in there really as a
run saving position more so than a
catchable I'm gonna hit the ball that
hard it's particularly tough for him
[Applause]
the cat to Naomi
I wonder it's gone past because it was
pained
is it a great example we're talking
about survivors a guy with Matthew
Hayden he's looking to get forward here
the ball was duggard in short but he's
good enough well he's off the front foot
really he's in weather and a half out of
his crease playing a poor shot
have the time to do that is a great
skill a few Indian feels when thinking
that was a chance but that's just hit
too well
this is draw of smackdown quick pitch
the show us family
[Applause]
oh that's a very
his first Iver
just a little bit slack there
let's shock played straight back just
watch this study whatever but did he
close the face while he just popped it
back and was nicely taken one hand and
it went back quicker than he
that's a very very good catch good
delivery had disturbed in on them Andrew
Symonds just a little bit to encourage
him to hit on the onside and enough spin
to get the leading edge but the catch
was the brilliant part
to 141
[Music]
heh-heh
ten meters apart
as far as score in Australia the one day
first 44 times in recent years in the
one-day internationals and has a score
200 there it goes superbly timed Hayden
on 98
[Applause]
this feels
there's one short called the ball before
to happening
[Applause]
any chance because a second
give us an ovation for brightenings
miss Matthew Hayden seen to that that's
the little short when he was on 99 in
the air
first
[Applause]
good supporting role
I was 98 this was a single to making 99
Dean not to have made it over that line
totally I was diving back 300 bed in the
find out he's only ninety nine still
that's the end of the 31st over
Pinkley parties lirikten estate market
but if I spin suppose
it's beautifully priory just dropped an
affection show and Clark
Goodyear's to the fade back quite a
regulation for shopping he hid his back
foot going well behind the stamps that's
beautifully played
in the air man and I should get to it to
touch it
[Applause]
baaji strike down his strike first
what a mess
[Applause]
it's gone this time
is responding
[Applause]
this man and the captain went to
he was spreading easy
Jordan Elena hey
before sewing up
[Applause]
go straight
to actually chop
detective game
at Lake stop clock was too good
there's a beautiful shot
he picked place quite a Liberty here at
square there any current between two men
are not all that
put that bond market Bevin and
dangerous man to have
fielding side Bevin is so experienced
we've seen him by quite calmly in
difficult situations more recently in
the World Cup
[Music]
keeps his head hasn't done anything at
all in this competition so far but in a
big age on that
[Applause]
Studios ground remodel every
but Phil Steve back
[Applause]
[Music]
right down the toe
India's chances have been preached and
Australia we're going to struggle from
now on
Bevan I'll have to take a
six for 224 Michael Pak played very well
42 from 45 he's gone
so why why with the boundary
not surprising with the shortcut
bobby was ready for it
it was a good shot but I'm not too sure
it was a good delivery first up time
because the bowler has been moving the
ball of the scene when he gets it up to
the best man
in here it's in the day at school
his best
[Applause]
me
seven for 249
woods safe cats in the outfield under
pressure
there's a big wicked because it means
now that Michael Bevins playing with the
bowlers rather than a man who was
capable of hitting some boundaries and
doing a fair bit of damage himself in
safe cash they're taken by Gavaskar 7/4
to 49
it's gone trip takes the catch
[Applause]
intelligent Boeing
he's gone
thirty out of 24
he's kept a very cool head in this
situation Balaji really the only thing
he's done wrong in this game is to drop
a catch on the boundary outside of that
he's had a very very good match
soli gone is tight for 266
[Applause]
sure
the gap down to 11
too short and he gave the Bevin a lot of
areas to hit that Paul finally comes up
Chrissa to deep cover and the katene is
changed around the bars
[Applause]
first announced very cars
it was a very good round I think it's
curved ask you again
under pressure keeping his pool
throw was near the bales aboah did well
and where's the batsman is out is it now
photo finish visible
yep well they'll give that out
very good piece of work there by Jayson
Velez be full stretch
he's just got home it was an excellent
piece of fielding the throw was right
next to the stumps the ballad she was in
the right position as he actually took
the ball at brought his hand onto the
stumps
a single SPF just stretched out enough
good piece of our building great running
by the big man is happy so he should be
its 23 up 11 sprayer steel whip hairs to
pick up good throw
maybe the bar was should have been in
other side of the stump she had to turn
back a fraction but right running by
Gillespie just made it big tall man
stretching I was just a fraction wide
excellent cricket under pressure from
both teams he does in here
[Applause]
parrot
young cricketer Mohsin
that was a great catch under pressure
yes he covered a lot of territories come
from the cover position but the
important thing is here he wanted the
ball he was off immediately not hanging
around waiting to see if somebody else
was going to get there kept his eye on
it all the way
you catch
so the young guys doing a terrific job
in this situation for India it's mine
for 282
[Applause]
if you woke up this should be run there
Joey that's it that's the big
by 20 rounds
built wish to hide
a big big victory for India
excellent fuel car there from Qatar and
finally they produced the hip
that's a good win to India they've added
very well
they've bowled extremely well most of
their fielding was was good they've
certainly deserved this victory Laxman
and Tendulkar setting it up setting a
very good foundation early on and the
young bowlers have been the ones that
have been impressive in these final few
overs and
Gavaskar making a good day boo got a
wicked brilliant port involved and did
some good work in the outfield so it's
been an impressive victory by India
particularly because the answers have
contributed so much to the victory
for 284
young lion stood firm I felt with the
ball Bhutan Balaji and Gavaskar chipping
for pretty big wicket his first over so
very good all their performance was a
batsman spits here today at the Gabba
they defended 303 they've got a big
victory